Verle G. Kaiser Papers 1932-1982
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
- The Palouse, Series 10
  - Soil Conservation Plan, E.C. Huntley Farm, 1946; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1334)
  - Soil Conservation Plan, J.W. Maxwell Farm, 1946; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1335)
  - Soil Conservation Service, Pullman Experiment Station, 1935-1981; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1336)
  - Soil Conserving and Improving Crop Rotations for the Palouse, 1939; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1337)
  - Soil Experiment Investigations Progress Report, Pullman, 1931-1935; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1338)
  - Soil Moisture Data, 1955-1956; 9 items. (Box 23, Folder 1339)
  - Soil Organic Matter, 1954; 8 items. (Box 23, Folder 1340)
  - South Fork, Palouse River Map, 1934; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1341)
  - South Palouse Soil Conservation District Newsletter, 1960; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1342)
  - Special Fields to Watch, 1942; 51 items. (Box 23, Folder 1343)
  - Special Fields to Watch, undated; 41 items. (Box 23, Folder 1344)
  - Standards for Conservation Treatment, North and South Palouse, 1939-1959; 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 1345)
  - Standards for Conservation Treatment, North and South Palouse, undated; 10 items. (Box 23, Folder 1346)
  - Steptoe Butte, Cashup Davis Maps, undated; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 1347)
  - Stripcropping and Control Farming, 1947-1962; 24 items. (Box 23, Folder 1348)
  - Stripcropping and Control Farming, 1949-1953; 13 items. (Box 23, Folder 1349)
  - Stripcropping and Control Farming, 1965-1971; 32 items. (Box 23, Folder 1350)
  - Stubble Mulch, 1945-1947; 12 items. (Box 23, Folder 1351)
  - Stubble Mulch, 1951-1960; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 1352)
  - Suggested Outline for a "Palouse Program" in Spokane County, 1981; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1353)
  - Sulphur and Legumes, 1944-1954; 14 items. (Box 23, Folder 1354)
  - Sulphur and Phosphorus, 1947-1965; 8 items. (Box 23, Folder 1355)
  - "Summer Fallow Funeral," by Verle G. Kaiser, Reddy Koloust Farm News, undated; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1356)
  - Supplement to the Environmental Statement, Department of the Interior Proposed Program for the Bonneville Power Administration, 1976; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1357)
  - Sweet Clover as Green Manure, 1960; 30 items. (Box 23, Folder 1358)
  - Sweet Clover Field Investigation, 1955-1956; 14 items. (Box 23, Folder 1359)
  - Sweet Clover Field Trials, 1945-1954; 17 items. (Box 23, Folder 1360)
  - Sweet Clover In-Crop Rotations, Master Tables, 1939-1955; 26 items. (Box 23, Folder 1361)
  - Tabular and Graph Data Soil Loss Studies, Dayton, Washington, 1946; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1362)
  - Talk on the Palouse with Slides, undated; 26 items. (Box 23, Folder 1363)
  - Teacher-Conservation Workshop, Whitman County, W.S.U., 1955; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1364)
  - Technical Guide for M.L.R.A. Number Nine, Palouse and Nez Perce Prairie Alternative Cropping Systems, 1963; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1365)
  - Technical Guide for Soil and Water Conservation, Pine Creek Soil Conservation District, Whitman County, Washington, 1954; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1366)
  - The Economic Results of Erosion Control Program, South Fork of the Palouse Project, 1936; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1367)
  - "The Future of the Palouse: Productive Wheatland Grassland, or Desert?" by Verle Kaiser, 1952; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1368)
  - "The Future of the Palouse: Productive Wheatland Grassland, or Desert?" by Verle Kaiser, 1953; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1369)
  - The Influence of Absentee Landowners on Use of Erosion Control Practices by Palouse Farmers, 1978; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1370)
  - The Palouse Erosion Laboratory, 1964; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1371)
  - The Use of Soil Conditioners, 1952-1953; 16 items. (Box 23, Folder 1372)
  - The Wheat Allotment and Soil Erosion in the Palouse, by Verle Kaiser, 1977; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1373)
  - The Young Men and Women in Whitman County Schools, 1947; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1374)
  - "Thoughts on Acreage Program for Lincoln County," by Verle Kaiser, 1957; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1375)
  - "Thoughts on Acreage Program for Lincoln County," by Verle Kaiser, 1960; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1376)
  - Tillage Systems for Conservation in the Palouse, 1979; 12 items. (Box 23, Folder 1377)
  - Topographic Soil Diagram of a Typical Palouse Hill and Possible Topographic Development of Typical Hills, 1944; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 1378)
  - Topographic Types, Distribution of Different Land Forms in Whitman County, Washington, 1963; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 1379)
  - Topography and Soil Surveys, 1949-1953; 18 items. (Box 23, Folder 1380)
  - Topography and Soil Surveys, 1960-1981; 20 items. (Box 23, Folder 1381)
  - Trails Through the Palouse, John Mullan Survey, 1859; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1382)
  - Transparent Maps, undated; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 1383)
  - "Types of Typography as Related to Land Use in Whitman County, Washington," Northwest Science, 1949; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1384-1385)
  - USDA SCS Cooperative Agreement with Lue Hofer, 1937; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1386)
  - Verle Kaiser Note to H.E. Russell, Spokane, on Northwest Sciences Meeting Presentation, 1966; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1387)
  - Virgin vs. Cultivated Land, 1950; 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 1388)
  - Washington State University Field Days, 1978; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1389)
  - Washington Agriculturalist, "Seventy-Five Years of Progress through Agriculture", 1965; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1390)
  - Watershed Plan, Pleasant Creek Creek, Whitman County, 1981; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1391)
  - Weeds, A Palouse Problem, 1961; 20 items. (Box 23, Folder 1392)
  - Weeds, A Palouse Problem, 1961; 28 items. (Box 23, Folder 1393)
  - Westward by Covered Wagon to a Homestead in Latah, 1976; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1394)
  - Wheat Culture, Palouse and Pacific Northwest, 1961; 26 items. (Box 23, Folder 1395)
  - Wheat Diseases: Snow Mold, Stripe Rust, 1961; 22 items. (Box 23, Folder 1396)
  - Wheat Program, 1978; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 1397)
  - Wheat: Relation of Yield to Soil and Erosion, 1981; 25 items. (Box 23, Folder 1398)
  - Wheat Yield, 1919-1939; 19 items. (Box 24, Folder 1399)
  - "Wheatland Wildlife," Washington State Game Department, 1950; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 1400)
  - Whitman County: Annual Soil Loss by Water Erosion, 1939-1978; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1401)
  - Whitman County Historical Newsletter, 1979; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1402)
  - Whitman County, Wash., Conservation Agreements, undated; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 1403)
  - Whitman County Wheat Yield Data, 1933-1970; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 1404)
  - Whitman Soil Lab Recommendations for use of Nitrogen Fertilizers, undated; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1405)
  - Winter Wheat on Summerfallow Near Pullman, undated; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1406)
  - Working Agreement for Erosion Control on the Palouse Cove Road, 1946; 20 items. (Box 24, Folder 1407)
- Soil Conservation, Series 11
  - American Assembly: "Uses of the Sea", 1969; 11 items. (Box 24, Folder 1408)
  - Basic Data: Land Use and Cropping Patterns for Twenty-Five Grain-Producing Counties, 1964; 7 items. (Box 24, Folder 1409)
  - Biography of Hugh Bennett and other Conservation Leaders, 1959-1969; 17 items. (Box 24, Folder 1410)
  - Conservation of the Camp Site, by the American Camping Association, 1960; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1411)
  - Copies of Field Survey Sheets, First Soil Survey of the North Palouse SCD, early 1940's; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1412)
    - Number Two, 1940's; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1413)
  - Development and Resources Corporation, undated; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1414)
  - Dryland Conservation Farming, Lower Columbia River Basin, 1957; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 1415)
  - Early American Soil Conservationists, USDA, 1941; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1416)
  - Farm Programs and Farmer-Consumer Relations, 1949-1966; 27 items. (Box 24, Folder 1417)
  - Federal Council for Science and Technology Committee on Water Resources Research, Office of Science and Technology, 1966; plus a covering letter from Senator Warren G. Magnuson, 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1418)
  - History and Organization of Soil Conservation Service, 1935-1971; 24 items. (Box 24, Folder 1419)
  - Idaho Soil and Water Conservation Needs Inventory, 1963; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1420)
  - Information about Soil and Water Conservation Districts, Pacific Northwest, 1937-1967; 27 items. (Box 24, Folder 1421)
  - Journal of Soil and Water Conservation, 1978; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1422)
  - Land Capability for Soil and Water Conservation in Idaho, 1951; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1423)
    - Oregon, 1953; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1424)
    - Washington, 1950; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1425)
  - Land Resource Regions and Major Land Resource Areas of the U.S., 1965; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1426-1427)
  - Land Utilization Projects: General Map of the U.S., 1937; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 1427)
  - Mailing Addresses, Soil Conservation District Supervisors and Offices, 1949-1964; 15 items. (Box 24, Folder 1428)
  - Mailing Addresses, Soil Conservation District Supervisors and Offices, 1966-1979; 10 items. (Box 24, Folder 1429)
  - Man as a Revolutionary Element of Conservation, The Road to Change, by David E. Lilienthall, 1964; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1430)
  - Missouri Flat Creek Field Data, 1976; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 1431)
  - Missouri Flat / South Fork Project, Cover and Treatment Surveys, 1940; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1432)
  - Missouri Flat Summary Data, 1978; 27 items. (Box 24, Folder 1433)
  - National Association of Conservation Districts Tuesday Letter, 1977; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1434)
  - Notes on Conservation Program, Kuhn Brothers' Farm, 1960; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 1435)
  - Philosophy and History of Soil Conservation, 1943-1966; 41 items. (Box 24, Folder 1436)
  - Philosophy and History of Soil Conservation, 1945-1970; 34 items. (Box 24, Folder 1437)
  - Philosophy and History of Soil Conservation, 1969-1971; 14 items. (Box 24, Folder 1438)
  - Precipitation: Heat and Moisture Indexes For Use in Capability Classification, undated; 2 items. (Box A, Folder 1439-1440)
  - Precipitation: Northern Idaho and Inland Empire, undated; 7 items. (Box A, Folder 1441)
  - Precipitation Rainfall and Water Conservation in the U.S., 1965; 1 item. (Box A, Folder 1442)
  - Precipitation Relations Between Plant Growth and Transpiration, 1962; 2 items. (Box A, Folder 1443)
  - Precipitation, 1962; 4 items. (Box A, Folder 1444)
  - Precipitation- Washington State: Intensity, Frequency Duration Zones of Rainfall, 1964; 14 items. (Box A, Folder 1445)
  - Precipitation-Whitman County Records, 1944-1977; 78 items. (Box A, Folder 1446)
  - Problem Areas, State of Washington: SCS, 1955 (Box A, Folder 1447)
  - RC and D Project, Farm Conservation Treatment, undated; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 1448)
  - Reorganizations of the SCS: Its Relationship to other Agencies, 1936-1965; 23 items. (Box 25, Folder 1449)
  - Reorganizations of the SCS: Its Relationship to other Agencies, 1936-1965; 11 items. (Box 25, Folder 1550)
  - Soil Conservation Service Maps, Pacific Northwest, 1948; 108 items. (Box 25, Folder 1451)
  - Soil and Water Conservation for Dryfarmlands of the Columbia River Basin: What We Are Doing and What Should Be Done, by Verle Kaiser, 1965; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 1452)
    - Needs Inventory: The Oregon Conservation Needs Committee, 1962; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1453)
  - Soil Conservation District Publications, 1946-1956; 10 items. (Box 25, Folder 1454)
  - Soil Conservation District Publications, 1952-1971; 34 items. (Box 25, Folder 1455)
  - Soil Conservation District Publications, 1965-1971; 16 items. (Box 25, Folder 1456)
  - Soil Conservation Service Maps, 1952; 174 items. (Box 25, Folder 1457)
  - Soil Survey, Benton County, Washington: Washington Agricultural Experiment Station, 1971; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1458)
  - Soil Survey - Spokane County, Washington, 1968; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1459)
  - Speeches on Religion and Conservation, 1950; 10 items. (Box 25, Folder 1460)
  - Training in Agronomy, San Luis Obispo, Ca., 1958; 10 items. (Box 25, Folder 1461)
  - USDA Report on Water and Related Land Resources, Hood Drainage Basin, Oregon, 1962; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1462)
  - USDA Report on Water and Related Land Resources, Hood Drainage Basin, Oregon, 1964; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1463)
  - Washington Soil and Water Conservation Needs Inventory, 1962; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1464)
  - Washington Soil and Water Conservation Needs Inventory, 1970; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1465)
  - Washington Soil and Water Conservation Needs Inventory, 1970; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 1466)
  - Washington Soils Classification, 1965; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 1467)
  - Whitman County and Northern Idaho Precipitation Records, 1942-1980; 35 items. (Box 25, Folder 1468)
  - World Resources, Food, Population, 1942-1951; 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 1469)
  - World Resources, Food, Population, 1965-1980; 23 items. (Box 25, Folder 1470)
- Series 12: Maps and Graphs
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Services Farm File records, circa 1940s (Box 26, Folder 1471)
  - Supplement to Soil Survey of Whitman County, Washington, USDA, Soil Conservation Service (145 leaves, primarily maps), 1980 (Box 26, Folder 1472)
  - "Conservation Plan Map" (aerial photograph), Latah County, ID, Palouse River Basin, USDA Soil Conservation Service, 1976 June (Box Oversize, Folder 1473)
  - Whitman County, WA road maps, 1950, 1956 (Box Oversize, Folder 1474)
  - Whitman County, WA road map (reproduction with annotations), 1968 (Box Oversize, Folder 1475)
  - US Geological Survey topographical map, modified to show "South Fork of the Palouse Erosion Control Demonstration Project, 1933-1939", 1958 (Box Oversize, Folder 1475)
  - Map of Columbia-North Pacific drainage region, USDA Soil Conservation Service, 1965 (Box Oversize, Folder 1475)
  - Whitman County, WA map: "Water Erosion Damage," USDA Soil Conservation Service, 1968 (Box Oversize, Folder 1476)
  - (Box September)
  - Map of Trapper Creek Elk Hunting area (reproduction of manuscript map), undated (Box Oversize, Folder 1476)
  - Maps showing David Thompson's 1811 route (manuscript maps and annotated printed maps), circa 1950s-1960s (Box Oversize, Folder 1476)
  - Whitman County, WA maps: soil erosion survey, 1939-1972 (Box Oversize, Folder 1477)
  - Whitman County, WA maps: water erosion damage, circa 1939-1980 (Box Oversize, Folder 1478)
  - Palouse River Basin maps and aerial photographs, circa 1970s (Box Oversize, Folder 1479)
  - Conservation cropping systems specifications and notes, 1963-1964; 1981 (Box Oversize, Folder 1480)
  - Maps, Spokane County comprehensive land use plan, 1978 (Box Tube 1)
  - Map showing Palouse Prairie housing density (manuscript; composite of layered transparencies and paper), 1979 (Box Tube 1)
  - Map of residences on Paradise Prairie (composite with printed and manuscript components on paper and transparency), 1979 (Box Tube 1)
  - Maps of unidentified location (4 manuscript maps), showing: straw spreading, types of cash crops, types of green manure used by farms, harvest treatment of crop residues, 1938 (Box Tube 2)
  - Whitman County, WA maps (printed maps with annotations) showing soil erosion information, circa 1940s-1950s (Box Tube 2)
  - Map of Osier-Moose Creek Basin (manuscript), circa 1950s-1960s (Box Tube 2)
  - Straw and wheat yield charts, Palouse Hills (manuscript), circa 1930s (Box Tube 3)
  - Erosion maps (manuscript and printed maps, some reproductions), undated (Box Tube 3)
  - Whitman County, WA aerial mosaic map, USDA Soil Conservation Service (photograph), 1971 (Box Tube 3)
  - Map of the Inland Empire (printed map, cut out and modified, hand colored), 1967 (Box Tube 4)
  - Map of Eastern Portion, Columbia Basin (manuscript, transparency), 1967 (Box Tube 4)
  - Palouse region space survey photographs, 1975 (Box Tube 4)
- Audio Recordings, Series 13
  - "A Critical Look at the Soil Erosion Problems of the Palouse" (Kaiser). (4 audiocassettes), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "The CCC and Its Soil Erosion Control--Working in the Inland Empire"; "A Critical Look at the Soil Erosion Problems of the Palouse, the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Problems of State of Washington." (3 audiocassettes), 1974, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - CCC--Rabdau--CCC continued, a 1977 Look at the Palouse Erosion Problem (Kaiser). (3 audiocassettes), 1977 and undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Columbia-Snake-Palouse Program-Phase II, Narrated by Wey Simpson, KHQ. Report of Task Force, Columbia-Snake-Palouse; Water Conservation. (3 audiocassettes), 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Geologic and Historic Background for the Palouse Region--SCSA Tours, Natural Resources Management and Standard of Living. (4 audiocassettes), circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Plat Hearing. (3 audiocassettes), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 6)